Mohanadas Harish Chandar



Blk 747 Pasir Ris St 71 #07-36 Singapore 510747

Phone: (65) 6584-2629 H/P: (65) 9088-3052

Email: harishcm.work@gmail.com

url: http://self-direct.info

Born: October 23, 1985—Singapore

Nationality: Singaporean

National Service Status: Completed

Degree

Bachelor of Engineering (Civil), National University of Singapore

Final Year Student, Expected June 2011, Current CAP: 4.29/5 (2nd Upper Honours)

Major coursework

Water Resources Engineering • Water and Wastewater Engineering • Air Quality Management • Geotechnical Engineering • Analytical and Numerical Methods in Foundation Engineering • Transportation Engineering • Transportation Management and Policy • Structural Analysis and Design • Offshore Structural Analysis and Design • Construction Project Management • Reliability Analysis and Design • Human Capital in Organisations

Electives

Natural Resources: Policy and Practice • Remote Sensing and Earth Observation

Project & research work

Design Project

Designed a temporary road diversion plan and a corresponding traffic signal plan to facilitate construction of a road tunnel next to a busy T-junction. The simulated situation was a road tunnel for motorists exiting Sentosa island for mainland Singapore.

Undergraduate Research Opportunities Programme (UROP)

Performed over 130 hours of lab work and participated in proceedings of the National UROP Congress. *Title*: "Basic behavior study of cement treated Singapore marine clay".

Education

- 2006-now BEng in Civil Engineering, National University of Singapore
- 2002-2003 Victoria Junior College, Singapore
- 1998-2001 Victoria School, Singapore
- 1996–1997 St Gabriel's Primary School, Singapore
 - 1995 St John's School, Scarborough, Western Australia
- 1992–1995 St Gabriel's Primary School, Singapore

Honors & awards

- 2009 Dean's List, Academic Year 2008/2009 Semester 2
- 2009 HDB Book Prize (2nd Prize for Beam Design Competition)
- 2002 SINDA Academic Excellence Award (for outstanding performance in GCE 'O' Levels)
- 2001 Victoria School GCE 'O' Level Award
- 2001 Distinguished Service Award (Monitors' Council)
- 2001 Meritorious Service Award (National Cadet Corps (Land))
- 2001 School Subject Prize (Best in Design and Technology)
- 1996-2001 Edusave Scholarships, Ministry of Education
 - 2000 School Subject Prize (Best in Tamil Language)
 - 2000 Singapore East Zone School Sports Council Team Award (for National 4th in Cricket)
 - 1999 Top Student Award (3rd in Standard)

Positions held

- 2009-now Member, Ground-Up Initiative—Local NGO
- 2006-now Section Commander (Reservist), 778 SIR, Singapore Armed Forces
- 2004-2006 Section Commander, 5 SIR, Singapore Armed Forces
- 2002-2003 Student Councillor, Victoria Junior College
- 2000-2001 Head of Welfare, Monitors' Council, Victoria School
- 2000–2001 Outdoor Pursuit Camp Instructor, Victoria School
- 2000-2001 Staff Sergeant, National Cadet Corps (Land)

Competitions

- 2001 Distinction, International Science Competition for Schools, Uni. of New South Wales
- 2000 National Champion, National Cadet Corps Shooting Competition
- 2000 National 4th, Cricket
- 1995 High Distinction, Primary Schools Mathematics Competition, Uni. of New South Wales

Work experience

Engineer Intern, Engineers 9000 Pte Ltd, Singapore

Jul 2010

May 2010- Designed a small concrete bridge with steel guardrails. Verified changes to drawings and calculations for industrial structures, checking for structural stability and adequacy. Reported discrepancies to supervising engineer and recommended modifications. Gained experience in detailing of reinforced concrete members and design of steel connections. Gained basic understanding about document submission procedures to regulatory authorities for civil and structural works.

Lifequard, Paramount's King's Dominion, Virgina, USA

May 2007 - Experienced working in a multicultural environment in the USA. Worked hand in hand with the local Americans and other foreigners from Asia, Eastern Europe and South America.

Section Commander, 5th Singapore Infantry Regiment, Singapore Armed Forces

Sep 2004 Lead and ensured the operational readiness and welfare of a 7-person combat section. Mar 2006 Understood what it takes to train, lead and manage teams under difficult and stressful situations. Understood what it takes to gain the respect of one's superiors and subordinates at the same time.

Hobbies and interests

Urban Farming, Gardening and Permaculture

Assisted a local NGO—Ground Up Initiative—in setting up a rooftop garden concept model. Volunteered at local farms and community gardens, and attended courses in Permaculture design. Learnt critical observation skills and patience, and experienced working with nature.

Libre and Open Source Software

Great interest and considerable experience with libre and open source software such as Linux (operating system), GNUCash (finance), GIMP (image editing), and FreeMind (mind mapping). Opened my mind towards exploring alternatives and adapting them to my workflows to improve productivity.

Skills

Technical Document Typesetting

Skilled at typesetting professional looking technical documents, particularly those that are long and complex, and contain several equations, tables, figures, cross-references, etc.. Cultivated an appreciation of aesthetics and a large degree of meticulousness when required.

Productivity Software

Excellent Microsoft Office, OpenOffice, Internet and Email applications

Good Linux (operating system)

Good GNUCash (finance)

Good Vim (text editing)

Good IkiWiki (website creation)

Good GIMP (image editing)

Good LaTeX (technical writing and typesetting)

Fair Bazaar (document version control)

Engineering Software

Excellent COMSOL Multiphysics (general numerical modeling)

Fair Plaxis and SIGMA/W (geotechnical modeling)

Good SIDRA (transportation and traffic modeling)

Good USFOS (offshore structural modeling) and BEAMD (beam design)

Fair STAAD.Pro (structural design)

Good AutoCAD and QCAD (drafting)

Good Primavera (project management)

Good GRASS GIS, ArcGIS and TNTmips (geographical information systems & remote sensing)

Languages

Excellent English
Excellent Tamil

References

Professor Somsak Swaddiwudhipong

Deputy Head (Academic), Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, National

University of Singapore Phone: (65) 6516-2173

Email: cvesomsa@nus.edu.sg

Additional References

Available on request.

Last updated: March 10, 2011 • Typeset in X₃T_EX http://self-direct.info/about/resume.pdf